Theodor Reik Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings File, 1911-1994 (Box 7-18)
  - By Reik (Box 7)
    - Notes on (Box 9)
      - Judaism (Box 9)
        - Set 3, partially from Part III of Curiosities of the Self, circa 1959-1961, (3 folders) (Box 10)
        - Set 3, partially from Part III of Curiosities of the Self, circa 1959-1961, (4 folders) (Box 11)
        - Set 4, bibliography, undated (Box 11)
        - Set 5, "Ergänzungen zu Pagan Remnants in Judaism," undated (Box 11)
        - Set 6, miscellaneous, undated (Box 11)
      - Language, undated (Box 11)
      - Listening, undated (Box 11)
      - "Man, the Moral Climber," circa 1945-1953 (Box 11)
      - Men and women, circa 1945-1953 (Box 11)
        - From topically labeled envelopes (Box 11)
          - "Active/passive" (Box 11)
          - "[Double] standards" (Box 11)
          - "Dress" (Box 11)
          - "Homosexuality" (Box 11)
          - "Infection" (Box 12)
          - "Introduction" (Box 12)
          - "Male and female varia" (Box 12)
          - "Masochism" (Box 12)
          - "Men women" (Box 12)
          - "Men women III", (3 folders) (Box 12)
          - "Nature", (3 folders) (Box 12)
          - "Prehistory" (Box 12)
          - "Sex", (4 folders) (Box 13)
          - "Varia (biology, intercourse, emotional differences)" (Box 13)
          - "Wit" (Box 13)
          - "Young Men" (Box 13)
        - From unlabeled packets, (10 folders) (Box 14)
        - From unlabeled packets, (5 folders) (Box 15)
      - Readings, bibliographic notes, undated (Box 15)
      - "Technik," undated (Box 15)
      - Various topics, circa 1941-1964, (2 folders) (Box 15)
      - "Wert der Neurose," undated (Box 15)
    - Reprints and copies of journal articles, 1911-1968, (7 folders) (Box 16)
    - Speeches (Box 17)
      - "From a speech to students," 1962 (Box 17)
      - Speech on psychoanalysis, undated See Container OV 6, same heading (Box 17)
    - Torn fragments, undated (Box 17)
    - Unidentified English manuscripts (Box 17)
      - Set 1, 1966-circa 1969 (Box 17)
      - Set 2, undated, (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - Sets 3-4, undated See also Container OV 7, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - Sets 5-7, undated See Container OV 7, same heading (Box 17)
  - By others (Box 17)
    - Berlin, Jeffrey B., 1971-1982 (Box 17)
    - Ivins, Barbara, 1944, (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - Jeffery, Dorothy, 1954 (Box 17)
    - Kraus, Karl, Die Fackel, 1928 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
      - B-D, 1951-1994 (Box 18)
      - E-J, 1948-1968 (Box 18)
      - K-M, 1945-1968 (Box 18)
      - N-S, 1950-1952, undated (Box 18)
      - T-Z, 1952-1975, undated (Box 18)
    - Pan issues, 1911-1913 (Box 18)
    - Sherman, Murray H., 1974, undated (Box 18)
    - Unidentified, 1914, 1978, undated (Box 18)
- Oversize, 1911-1962 (Box OV 1-OV 7)
  Drafts of handwritten manuscripts on oversize sheets of paper, often filed with accompanying notes and printed matter; newspaper and magazine clippings of articles by Reik; and a certificate.
  Arranged according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Personal and Family Papers (Box OV 1)
    - Certificate as psychologist, awarded by the University of the State of New York, 1959 (Container 1, New York State psychologist certificate) (Box OV 1)
  - Gustav Mahler (Box OV 1)
    - Binders (Containers 3-6, same heading) (Box OV 1)
      - Large sheets of handwritten notes and drafts, with related concert programs, reprints, and news clippings, from Binders A-C, 1925-1947, undated, (6 folders) (Box OV 1)
      - Large sheets of handwritten notes and drafts, with relate typed drafts, concert programs, reprints, and news clippings, from Binder C, 1933-1950, undated, (2 folders) (Box OV 2)
    - Loose handwritten notes and drafts on large sheets, largely in German, undated (Container 6, same heading), (2 folders) (Box OV 2)
    - Copy of a portrait drawing and published photograph of a bronze bust, undated (Container 6, Portrait drawings) (Box OV 2)
    - Facsimile edition of Mahler's Symphony no. 10, 1924 (Container 7, same heading) (Box OV 2)
  - Writings File (Box OV 3)
    - By Reik (Box OV 3)
      - Book drafts and notes (Box OV 3)
        - Handwritten and typed drafts, some on large sheets, of the chapter "Aria Without Words" ("Three Women in a Man's Life"), circa 1953 (Container 7, The Haunting Melody ) (Box OV 3)
        - Handwritten drafts and notes on large sheets, circa 1962 (Container 7, Jewish Wit ), (7 folders) (Box OV 3)
        - Preface and outline on large sheets, circa 1957 (Container 8, Myth and Guilt ) (Box OV 3)
        - Handwritten draft on large sheets of "The Chip on the Shoulder" from Part III, circa 1957 (Container 8, Of Love and Lust ) (Box OV 4)
        - Handwritten drafts and notes from Part IV: "The Emotional Differences of the Sexes," circa 1957 (Container 8, Of Love and Lust ), (2 folders) (Box OV 4)
      - German manuscripts, handwritten on large sheets (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 5)
        - Set 1, dated drafts with journal-like entries and some Gustav Mahler-related notes, 1938-1941 (Box OV 5)
        - Set 2, drafts on Judaism, largely on Jewish humor, undated (Box OV 5)
        - Set 3, miscellaneous drafts from Der Überraschte Psychologe, writings on Jewish humor, and other works, undated (Box OV 5)
        - Set 4, miscellaneous drafts, including ones titled "Der Kleine König," "Ein Denkexperiment," "Kindermunde," and "Neo. Psych.," undated (Box OV 5)
      - Individual chapters or articles, handwritten drafts on large sheets (Box OV 6)
        - "The Courage of a Coward," undated (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 6)
        - "An Experimenter and His Audience," undated (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 6)
        - Freud, Sigmund, letters to Reik, handwritten English translations, 1911-1938 (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 6)
        - "Guilt Feeling," undated (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 6)
        - "Sexual Psychology in an American Novel," undated (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 6)
        - "Some Traits of Feminine Sexuality," undated (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 6)
      - Newspaper and magazine articles (Box OV 6)
        - Originals, 1913-1961 (Container 9, same heading), (4 folders) (Box OV 6)
      - Speeches (Box OV 6)
        - Speech on psychoanalysis, handwritten on large sheets, undated (Container 9, same heading) (Box OV 6)
      - Unidentified English manuscripts, handwritten on large sheets//*[local-name()='did' and count(child::*[local-name()='unittitle'])=0] (Box OV 7)
        - Sets 3-4, undated (Container 17, same heading), (2 folders) (Box OV 7)
        - Sets 5-7, undated (Container 17, same heading), (8 folders) (Box OV 7)